How does the news shape the way we see the world?
كيف يمكن للأخبار أن تشكل الطريقة التى نرى بها العالم؟
Here's the world based on the way it looks -- based on landmass.
وإليك فى عالم مبنى على الطريقة الى يبدو بها – على أساس مساحة واسعة من اليابسة
And here's how news shapes what Americans see.
وهنا كيف تشكل الأخبار الطريقة التى يرى بها الأمريكيين العالم
This map -- (Applause) -- this map shows the number of seconds
هذه الخريطة – (تصفيق) – تبين هذه الخريطة عدد الثوانى
that American network and cable news organizations dedicated to news stories,
التى تخصصها الشبكات الأمريكية ومؤسسات الأنباء المتخصصة للأخبار،
by country, in February of 2007 -- just one year ago.
بحسب البلد، فى فبراير / شباط 2007 – أى منذ سنة واحدة فقط
Now, this was a month when North Korea agreed to dismantle its nuclear facilities.
هنا، الشهر الذى وافقت فيه كوريا الشمالية على تفكيك منشآتها النووية.
There was massive flooding in Indonesia.
كان هناك سيول فى أندونسيا.
And in Paris, the IPCC released its study confirming man's impact on global warming.
وفى باريس، أصدرت اللجنة الدولية للتغيرات المناخية دراسة تأكد تأثير الإنسان على الاحتباس الحرارى.
The U.S. accounted for 79 percent of total news coverage.
الولايات المتحدة محسوبة على 79 بالمئة من مجموع التغطية الإخبارية.
And when we take out the U.S. and look at the remaining 21 percent,
وعند اقصاء الولايات المتحدة والنظر الى الـ21 فى المئة المتبقية،
we see a lot of Iraq -- that's that big green thing there -- and little else.
نرى الكثير من العراق – هذا الشئ الأخضر هناك — وقليل فى أماكن أخرى.
The combined coverage of Russia, China and India, for example, reached just one percent.
وصلت التغطية المشتركة لروسيا والصين والهند، على سبيل المثال، الى واحد بالمئة.
When we analyzed all the news stories and removed just one story,
وعندما حللنا كل الأخبار مع إزالة خبر واحد،
here's how the world looked.
هكذا بدا العالم.
What was that story? The death of Anna Nicole Smith.
ماهى هذه القصة؟ وفاة آنا نيكول سميث.
This story eclipsed every country except Iraq,
طافت هذه القصة جميع البلدان باستثناء العراق،
and received 10 times the coverage of the IPCC report.
وحصلت على عشر مرات التغطية اللجنة الدولية للتغيرات المناخية.
And the cycle continues;
ولا تزال الدائرة مستمرة؛
as we all know, Britney has loomed pretty large lately.
كما نعرف، فبريتنى تظهر بشكل مبالغ فيه فى الآونة الأخيرة.
So, why don't we hear more about the world?
فلما لا نسمع أكثر عن العالم؟
One reason is that news networks have reduced the number of their foreign bureaus by half.
أحد الأسباب أن شبكات الأخبار قلصت عدد مكاتبها الخارجية للنصف.
Aside from one-person ABC mini-bureaus in Nairobi, New Delhi and Mumbai,
بخلاف شخص واحد فى مكتب إيه بى سى الصغير فى نيروبى ونيو دلهى ومومباي،
there are no network news bureaus in all of Africa, India or South America
لا يوجد مكاتب لشبكات الأخبار فى كل من أفريقيا والهند وجنوب أمريكا
-- places that are home to more than two billion people.
-- الأماكن التى يقطنها أكثر من ملياري شخص.
The reality is that covering Britney is cheaper.
الواقع هو أن تغطية بريتني أرخص.
And this lack of global coverage is all the more disturbing
وهذا النقص فى التغطية العالمية مثير للقلق
when we see where people go for news.
عندما نعرف أين يذهب الناس لمعرفة الأخبار.
Local TV news looms large,
التلفزيون المحلى يلوح بقوة،
and unfortunately only dedicates 12 percent of its coverage to international news.
ولكنه للأسف يخصص 12 بالمئة فقط من تغطيته للأخبار الدولية.
And what about the web?
وماذا عن الإنترنت؟
The most popular news sites don't do much better.
المواقع الإخبارية الأكثر شعبية لا تقدم أفضل بكثير.
Last year, Pew and the Colombia J-School analyzed the 14,000 stories
فى العام الماضى، حللت مدرستى الصحافة بيو وكولومبيا الـ14000 خبر
that appeared on Google News' front page.
التى ظهرت على الصفحة الأولى لجوجل للأخبار.
And they, in fact, covered the same 24 news events.
وهى فى الواقع تغطى 24 حدث إخبارى.
Similarly, a study in e-content showed that much of global news from U.S. news creators
وبالمثل، أظهرت دراسة عن المحتوى الإلكترونى أن أغلب أخبار العالم لصناع الأخبار فى الولايات المتحدة
is recycled stories from the AP wire services and Reuters,
هى تدوير لأخبار من وكالة أنباء اسوشييتد برس ورويترز،
and don't put things into a context that people can understand their connection to it.
ولا توضع فى السياق ما يمكن للناس معرفة علاقتهم بها.
So, if you put it all together, this could help explain why today's college graduates,
وهكذا، فان وضعت كل ذلك معاً، يمكن أن يساعد هذا على تفسير لماذا خريجى جامعات اليوم
as well as less educated Americans,
بالتوازي مع الأقل تعليماً فى الولايات المتحدة
know less about the world than their counterparts did 20 years ago.
يعرفون الأقل عن العالم عن أقرانهم قبل 20 عاماً.
And if you think it's simply because we are not interested,
وإن ظننت أننا ببساطة لا نهتم،
you would be wrong.
ستكون مخطئ.
In recent years, Americans who say they closely follow global news most of the time
فى السنوات الأخيرة، زادت نسبة الأمريكيين، الذين قالوا أنهم يتابعون أخبار العالم عن كثب
grew to over 50 percent.
بخمسين بالمئة.
The real question: is this distorted worldview what we want for Americans
السؤال الحقيقى هو: هل هذه النظرة المشوهة للعالم هي ماذا نريد أن نقدمه للأمريكيين
in our increasingly interconnected world?
فى عالمنا الذي يزداد ترابطاً؟
I know we can do better.
أعرف أننا يمكن أن نفعل افضل.
And can we afford not to? Thank you.
وهل لا يمكننا ذلك؟ شكراً.